<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<recipe>
    <name>Persian Saffron Rice With Tahdeeg</name>
    <indexCharacter>P</indexCharacter>
    <notes></notes>
    <servings>0</servings>
    <instructions>
1. NOTE: IF FIXING FOR ANOTHER RECIPE ON A WEEKNIGHT, FIX THE RICE ONE NIGHT BEFORE!

2. Wash the dry rice by putting the rice in a medium-sized bowl and adding cold tap water to about an inch above the rice and stir with your hand. Do not rub the rice grains between your fingers. Empty the water and repeat filling, stirring and emptying the water 2 more times until the water is almost clear. On the 4th time, fill the bowl with water up to an inch above the rice, and add 4 Tbsp of table salt. Stir the saltwater thoroughly. Let the rice sit in the salt brine for at least 1 hour.

3. After the rice has brined, fill a large thick-bottomed pot half full of water and bring to a boil. Add the rice and brine solution to the boiling pot. Boil the rice, stirring occasionally to prevent rice grains settling at the bottom of the pot until the rice grains are almost cooked (AKA al dente). To make sure you catch the rice at the right stage, start examining the rice grains about 5 minutes after you have started boiling it. Al Dente means the rice grains are cooked on the outer layer but still hard in the center (This will take about 7 minutes).

4. Strain the rice using a colander. Run cold tap water through the rice mixture in the colander to wash away some of the starch. Repeat the cold water rinse a second time. NOTE: Running cold water through the cooked rice at this stage ensures fluffier grains and that the rice is not sticky. Once the rice has been rinsed twice, leave it in the colander to drain.

5. While the boiled rice is draining, slice the onion into 1/4-inch slices.

6. Use a thick-bottomed, non-stick pot (can be the same as used for boiling the rice) and set the heat on medium high (4 or 5 out of a maximum 10 setting). Add a 3-to-1 mixture of oil and butter (3 Tbsp of oil and 1 Tbsp of butter) Butter is used for flavor and oil is used to help prevent the bottom of the pot from burning. Add 2 Tbsp of the saffron solution to the mixture of oil and butter in the pot. Add salt and fresh black pepper to taste. Swirl the saffron flavored oil mixture around to ensure thorough coverage of the bottom and about 2 inches up the sides of the pot to prevent the rice and tahdeeg from sticking to the pot. Lay the sliced onion in the bottom of the pot, making sure to get the fullest coverage. Apply salt and black pepper to the top side of onion slices at the bottom of the pot. Transfer the steamed rice from the colander into the pot, in a mound on the onion slices. Using the handle of a spoon or spatula, poke 8-10 holes in the mound of rice reaching all the way down to the tahdeeg layer. Mounding the rice and poking the holes in the mound allows the steam to rise from the bottom of the pot to make a crunchier tahdeeg and ensure the middle of the mound cooks thoroughly. Put the lid on the pot and cook on medium high setting (dial setting 5 out of 10) Cook for 5 minutes or until condensation gathers on the inside of the lid and starts to drip down to the sides of the lid. A glass lid makes this observation easy. If you don’t have a glass lid, check the inside of the lid after 5 minutes. Remove the lid and put 5-6 pieces of butter or margarine (each 1 Tbsp) on the top of the rice mound. Place a paper towel (or dishcloth) over the top of the pot and replace the lid to seal the pot. Lower the temperature to medium low setting (dial setting 3 or 4 out of 10).

7. Steam the rice for 45 minutes. After about 40 minutes, fill the kitchen sink with cold tap water about 4 inches deep.

8. After your 45 minutes of steaming the rice is complete, lift the lid, remove the towel, and admire the rice perfection you have made! Quickly carry the pot to the kitchen sink and place in the cold bath of water you made earlier (you'll hear a loud sizzle)! This cold bath helps separate the bottom crunchy layer (tahdeeg) and rice from the hot metal pot. Remove the pot from the cold-water bath and place on a towel on the kitchen counter.

9. Remove 2 cups of white rice from the pot and put in a bowl. Add 2 Tbsp of the saffron solution and candied barberries to the bowl. Add more melted butter, if desired. Mix thoroughly, then set aside to use in decorating the rice. Remove the contents of the rice pot in one of two ways: 1) Spoon the rice: Remove the rest of the white rice from the pot using a spatula or large spoon (until you reach the crunchy bottom tahdeeg layer) and transfer it to your serving platter. Remove the crunchy tahdeeg and place with your rice on the serving platter or on a separate platter. Cut the yogurt/rice tahdeeg into serving-sized pieces.2) Invert the pot: Place a serving platter (larger than your pot's diameter) on the open pot and invert holding both tightly together. This will cause the rice and crunchy tahdeeg layer to drop onto your serving platter Place the platter on the counter and gently remove the pot. If the crunchy tahdeeg did not separate perfectly, remove the remaining pieces from the pot using a spatula or spoon. Decorate the platter of rice with the barberry/rice mixture or serve it in a separate bowl.

</instructions>
    <ingredients>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>c</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>basmati rice</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>T</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>salt</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>6</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>T</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>butter, divided</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>T</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>oil</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1/2</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>c</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>saffron water, see separate recipe</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>ea</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>large onion</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>0</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>-</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Candied Barberries, see separate recipe</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
    </ingredients>
</recipe>
