<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<recipe>
    <name>Kalua Pig</name>
    <indexCharacter>K</indexCharacter>
    <notes></notes>
    <servings>0</servings>
    <instructions>Step 1 

I use a technique with my Weber Smokey Mountain (WSM) smoker that allows me to cook my food overnight without really having to tend to it too much. This is a great way to go if you want to eat a little earlier and you have better things to do at night, like sleep for instance. I load up the charcoal bowl of my WSM with unlit charcoal and dispense a chimney load of lit charcoal over the pile. This will burn down overnight and is pretty much a maintenance free way to barbecue especially with this recipe. I ended up cooking this meat for 16 hours. 

Step 2 

You prepare your meat by sprinkling the salt on all surfaces then loosely wrap in banana leaves. You then wrap the wrapped meat in the aluminum foil; this keeps the meat extremely moist and allows enough smoke in to give you authentic kalua pig flavor. 

Step 3 

Assemble the rest of the smoker and fill the water pan. Put the lid on and let the smoker pre-heat for around 10 minutes. Add the mesquite wood chips (presumably pre-soaked for at least an hour) onto the lit charcoal then add your twice-wrapped meat. Don't forget to start your timer. I have a thermometer that I stick in the top vent, which allows me to judge the temperature inside the smoker. I try to keep that temperature between 230-240F by adjusting the air intake vent at the bottom of the smoker. I keep on eye on it for a couple of hours and make sure that everything is going good, add some more wood chips and go to sleep. 

Step 4 

First thing in the morning, I check the smoker temperature (which is usually right where it was at the night before) and the charcoal in the bowl. If the temperature is running low and you don't have that much charcoal left in the bowl light a new batch in your chimney and add it to the smoker. By this time you should be around 10 or so hours into your kalua pig. 

Step 5 

Line a tray with any additional banana leaves. Remove the meat from the smoker and let it rest in a cookie sheet (or some other type of tray) for around 10 minutes. Remove the meat from the foil and leaves and place into the pre-lined tray. Shred the meat with a couple of forks and serve with sticky rice and Finadene sauce.</instructions>
    <ingredients>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>0</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>-</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Pork butts - however many you want to barbecue</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>0</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>-</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Hawaiian sea salt - or rock salt</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>0</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>-</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Banana leaves - enough to wrap each pork butt and for presentation (available in some Latin and Asian markets)</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>0</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>-</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Aluminum foil - or Ti leaves if you got them</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>0</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>-</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Charcoal - enough to keep your fire lit overnight.</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>0</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>-</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Mesquite wood chips</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
    </ingredients>
</recipe>
