<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<recipe>
    <name>Boneless Rib Roast with Yorkshire Pudding</name>
    <indexCharacter>B</indexCharacter>
    <notes></notes>
    <servings>0</servings>
    <instructions>Trim most of fat off the roast, leaving approximately ¼ in
Cross cut the fat about 1 in. apart.
Season with Hickory-Smoked Rub on all sides (right after buying the roast)
Cut 3 oz of the fat trimmings into ½ chunks.
Cover and refrigerate for at least 24 hours, or up to 4 days in advance
Grease roasting pan and scatter the fat trimmings in bottom of the pan
Put the roasting rack in the pan and put the roast on the rack
Slow roast at 250 for about 2 ½ hours until it is 125
Whisk 2 ½ c flour with 1 T kosher salt in a large bowl
Whisk 4 eggs in a large bowl.
Then whisk in 4 c whole milk
Whisk the egg mixture into the flour
Cover with plastic wrap and refrigerate
Take pie out of freezer
Remove roast from oven and check temperature. 
If at 125, move the roast to cutting board and cover with foil for at least 1 hour
Increase temperature of oven to 425
Strain fat trimmings. 
If measures less than 6 T, add oil to make up the difference
Add the fat back to the roasting pan.
Wait for the oven to come up to 425 before putting the pan back in the oven.
Once the fat is hot give the Yorkshire batter a quick whisk
Add it to the roasting pan for about 40-45 minutes.
Start cooking Brussels sprouts
When there is about 15 minutes left on the Yorkshire pudding, add 1 T oil to a 12 in pan.
When the oil just starts to smoke, the pan is hot enough.
Dry the roast and sear the roast on all side (about 5-7 minutes per side)
Let the roast rest until the Yorkshire pudding is done
Slice the roast in ¾ in slices
When the Yorkshire pudding is done, remove from oven and cut into squares (12-16 pcs)</instructions>
    <ingredients>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>ea</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Boneless Rib Roast With Substantial Fat Layer</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>ea</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Hickory-Smoked Rub</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions> see separate recipe</processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>2-1/2</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>c</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Flour</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>ea</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Eggs</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>c</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Whole Milk</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>0</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>-</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Avocado Oil</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions> as needed</processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
    </ingredients>
</recipe>
