<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<recipe>
    <name>Buffalo Wing Pizza Roll-Up</name>
    <indexCharacter>B</indexCharacter>
    <notes></notes>
    <servings>0</servings>
    <instructions>Dissolve salt, sugar, and yeast in the warm water and allow the yeast to proof. ("Proofing" the yeast is testing it for viability. It will develop foam which looks like the head of a beer. If it doesn't proof, the yeast is dead and should be discarded.) Proofing takes about 15 minutes. Place flour in a food processor fitted with a dough blade, and through the feed tube with the food processor running, slowly pour the proofed yeast mixture, until the dough comes together and is a cohesive mass. Transfer the dough to a floured board, and knead for about 5 minutes. Place in a bowl, cover with a clean dish towel and allow dough to rise, so that it roughly doubles in volume. (This will take about 30 minutes to an hour). The dough has risen enough if you make an indentation with your finger and it does not spring back.) Punch the dough down and allow it to rise again. (Allowing the dough to rise a second time gives it a finer texture.) Note: It will not rise as much the second time.

While the dough is rising, prepare the pizza topping. Heat 1 tablespoon of the oil over medium- high heat in a large saucepan and saute garlic and onions until they begin to soften. Add parsley, salt, and tomatoes. Cook for about 20 minutes to allow flavors to integrate. (Begin the chicken as described below, while the sauce is cooking.) Remove from heat and whisk in instant flour to thicken. Mix with an immersion blender, then set aside briefly.

While the sauce is cooking, in a separate fry pan, heat the other tablespoon of olive oil over medium high heat, and brown the ground chicken, breaking up the pieces as it cooks. When the ground chicken has browned, remove from heat, crumble in blue cheese, and stir in buffalo wing sauce and yogurt. Fold this mixture into the tomato sauce. If the mix is absolutely too runny for a pizza topping, add more instant flour.

Preheat oven to 450 degrees F. Divide the dough in half and stretch out 2 (14-inch) circles. Transfer them to pizza stones sprinkled with cornmeal. Top with the buffalo chicken pizza topping. Roll up and seal ends. Bake for 15 to 20 minutes, or until the dough is nicely browned.</instructions>
    <ingredients>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>0</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>-</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Pizza Dough:</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>tbsp</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Salt</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>tbsp</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Sugar</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1/4</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>oz</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>packet fast-acting yeast, fresh</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1-1/2</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>c</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>warm water, between 100 and  115 degrees F, as measured with a candy thermometer (any hotter will kill the  yeast, an organic; too cool and the yeast won't be activated)</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>c</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>all-purpose flour, plus some extra to knead the dough</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1/4</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>c</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>cornmeal, for pizza stones</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>0</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>-</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>-</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>0</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>-</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Pizza topping:</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>tbsp</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>olive oil</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>cloves</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>garlic, chopped</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>med</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>onions, chopped</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>tbsp</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>fresh parsley leaves, chopped</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1/4</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>tsp</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Salt</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>16</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>oz</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Can tomato chunks or chunky tomato sauce</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1/4</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>c</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>instant flour, or enough as need to thicken the pizza topping if it is too runny (recommended: Wondra)</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>lb</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>ground chicken</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>5</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>oz</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>blue cheese, preferably Treasure Cave lite</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>1/2</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>c</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>Buffalo wing sauce,  (preferably Anchor Bay Wing Sauce made with the recipe from the place where buffalo wings were originally invented)</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
        <ingredient>
            <quantity>6</quantity>
            <unitOfMeasure>oz container</unitOfMeasure>
            <ingredientName>non-fat plain yogurt</ingredientName>
            <processingInstructions></processingInstructions>
        </ingredient>
    </ingredients>
</recipe>
